Hi, my name is Chu and I'm a financial
planner at FWD Life Insurance
Philippines. Today we are going to talk
about the company first FWD. So
currently FWD is already running at
number one for the year 2025 for the
first quarter. Why? This is because FWD
has grown at
57%. This is based on new businesses
acquired during the first quarter of
2025. Now why is it a certain
achievement of FWD? That is because the
company is actually
uh have been performing since 2014. The
very first company that has made
insurance into a
digitalized product that is easier to uh
understand for clients and for agents
alike.
So FWD does promote changing the way
people feel about insurance and we do
celebrate living. Here are some of the
benefits of having a life insurance
products. Number one, a consistent way
of
having money in case your bread winner
or a certain person with an income pass
away. This means to say inheritors or
dependents can have a safety net or an
amount of money that can help them
recover after a person's uh or someone
has been deceased. Why? Because it is
said that it will take an average of 5
years for a family or for a household to
be able to recover if a bread winner
will pass away. Number two, this is also
a best way to be able to make sure that
assets are successfully
inherited by being able to pay estate
taxes. Let me clear up. Real estate
taxes and estate taxes are two different
things. Real estate taxes are what we
pay annually for having uh properties
like our house, buildings, lots. While
estate taxes are what are taxes
um for when inheritors are going to
inherit the pro the property. So if you
have passed away, your inheritors will
have estate tax or also what we call
inheritors tax. So that is currently at
6% and does not yet include the 1.5%
documentary staff and then the
professional uh fee for processing these
particular um papers. So the beauty of
life insurance is that it gives a heads
up or a money that your inheritors can
use to pay these kinds of taxes and
professional fees. So this is a
successful transition of wealth from the
first generation to the second or for
one generation to the next. And what's
also the beauty of this
particular product having a life
insurance as we all know not every one
of us are currently married have
descendants. So what that means is we
have ascendants or our parents and
sometimes we also have no one else or
those who what we call already orphan.
So if someone gives you a hand during
the your most vulnerable time,
especially when you're old and sick,
this particular life insurance policy
can be a good way of giving them a last
thank you. So you can make them your
beneficiaries for life insurance. This
way you can also be secured that while
you are alive someone is going to take
care of you. This is for single people.
What else? Since we are
also most of us are employed, self
self-employed or business owners. We are
what we call a key person. someone who
has income and is contributing to the
economy and to the household or to our
families which means to say that if ever
anything happens to us we are actually
the ones who are what we call head of
financing. So if ever income do stop,
life insurance coverage can actually
support the expenses of our household if
there's any kind of death, accident or
illness that will take place during our
lifetime. So what are the other
benefits? The other benefits of having a
life insurance is actually being able to
have a safety
net which means to say that we are
actually secured. We do have a piece of
mind and we already have a backup plan.
But it's actually a wrong way to say it.
It's not a backup plan. It's already
part of the plan to make sure that plan
A can be ex executed
properly. Which means to say having a
life insurance is actually giving you a
head start. And this is the next reason.
While I was working as a life insurance
agent, some of the veterans who are
honestly
uh already considered senior
citizens most likely have a high netw
worth individuals and do you know what
they teach us there? These veteran life
insurance agents or financial advisors
taught us that most of the high netw
worth individual do get what we call a
whole life insurance and they do get
this particular insurance the
traditional life insurance in bulk. Why?
Because the moment that you get one it
actually earns what we call a guaranteed
cash value. And these guaranteed cash
value do earn every year. So it do
accumulate uh
earning every year. So if the cash value
is earning value every year, they
actually have the option to be able to
source it or to use it for financing.
financing for business, financing to
acquire a new property, financing to
support whatever lifestyle that they're
going to use it for. So this way they
can control a certain amount of interest
rate because it is already found out
that these particular insurance products
actually give us a better interest rate
compared to other financial
institutions.
So these are just some of the benefits
that life insurance has and at the same
time if you are part of the top 1% who
are also wanting to secure that your
inheritors will be able to sustain
wealth or generate wealth consistently.
Life insurance is used to finance what
we call trust funds and that's why we
have trust fund babies. In case of those
who don't know some of the high netw
worth individual as we know only have
one or two kids and if something happens
to both of the parents then the
dependents the kids sometimes are minors
and these are how they set things up.
They create a trust fund. They get their
own life insurance in case something
happens to them. This particular life
insurance
uh is going to be given to these trust
funds. So instead of writing their
minors, their dependents, their children
who are below 18 years
old, they instead write their trust fund
as their beneficiaries. Why? Because
they are secured that their assets,
money and this particular sum coverage
will be managed professionally and can
be used to provide for their young
children. And the beauty of this
particular life insurance or this system
that was set up is to make sure 100%
successful
execution and transfer smooth transfer
of generational wealth. So what they do
they teach their
um minor that at a certain age they have
to get their own life insurance. again
make the trust fund their beneficiary so
that for the next generation they will
just do the same. It's a repeat of
cycle. So those are the things that I
know. I hope that you were able to learn
some good uh tips that you can also
execute in this lifetime. So if you do
want to make FWD and also make me your
financial advisor, financial planner
then do click our uh
online Q or what we call a website. I
will just provide you my contact details
in the description and comment section.
Thank you for listening. If you've
learned something new, do uh that does
help you in your life, make sure that
you like this video, share it your with
your friends and family, and hopefully
every one of us can be able to change
the way people feel about insurance and
at the same time celebrate living. Thank
you.